HANIYEH FATHOLAHI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: haniyeh.fath@gamil.com

Address: Dortmund, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/h-fatholahi



SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with more than 5 years of work experience in medium-sized and large companies providing software solutions in the fields of intelligent transportation, fleet tracking, payment and insurance systems. Also, I am skilled in system analysis, design and backend development.

my expertise is developing applications and APIs using Java and NodeJS including their related frameworks, technologies and tools like different databases - SQL and NoSQL databases. In addition, experienced in developing services for IoT devices such as management and communication services.

EXPERIENCES

MAY 2021 - MAR 2022

JAVA DEVELOPER IN INSURANCE CORE INSURANCE, DOTIN, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Designing and developing new functionalities for life insurance system
- Developing life insurance rest APIs
- Developing and support financial features
- Working on system optimization for high performances
- Cooperating with customers in order to achieve all SRS requirements and features

OCT 2016 - FEB 2021

R&D DEPARTMENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MAGFA, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Designing and developing fleet tracking services for GPS tracking systems
- Designing and developing APIs for fleet tracking applications and services
- Collaborating with Frontend team
- Cooperating with hardware development team in order to design a new tracking protocol on top of TCP
- Designing and developing a USSD Wrapper service for USSD based mobile payments

SEP 2016 – MAR 2020

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TOOBATECH, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Technical lead of Toobatel Instant messaging system project for Alzahra university
- Designing and developing Toobatel app services such as gif and sticker services
- Integrating university services with Toobatel app
- Backend development for customized web applications such as polling and survey systems
- Developing services for other teams such as BI and AI teams

SKILLS

	Solid Understanding	Worked With	Familiar with Or Intrigued by
Programming .	- Java	- JavaScript	- Typescript
languages	- NodeJS	- Python	0 "
Development tools/frameworks	SpringSpring BootHibernateExpress JSJSFMaven	- JPA - Swagger	- Gradle
Software engineering & methodologies	OOPAgileScrumSystem designDebug and Tshoot	Design PatternsGITCI/CDUnit TestingDDD	
Architecture	MicroserviceMVC	- SOA	
Web technologies	 RESTful APIs SOAP Webservices JSON HTTP JSP/Servlet Socket programming 	- JWT - jUnit	
IDEs and tools	 IntelliJ idea Netbeans Eclipse Webstorm Postman iReport SQL developer argoUML 	 Docker Apache tomcat verneMQ RabbitMQ Apache webserver Nginx jConsole jMeter 	 Kubernetes Jenkins Kafka Ansible
Databases	OracleMySQLMongoDBRedis	Neo4jPostgreSQLCassandra	
OS	- Windows - CentOS	- Ubuntu	
Project/Source control tools	GitLabBitBucketRedmineJira	- Trello	

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, ALZAHRA UNIVERSITY,

TEHRAN

Dissertation Title: "implementing IoT platform by customizing Openstack cloud computing Infrastructure APIs for collecting metrics from IoT nodes. "

CERTIFICATES

- Oracle Database 12c administration, LAITEC institute of Sharif University of Technology, Tehran
- Java 8 Standard Edition, LAITEC institute of Sharif University of Technology, Tehran

LANGUAGES

• **Persian:** Native

English: Fluent (TOEFL iBT certificate – C2)
 German: Basic (taking in A2 level classes)